Adedamola Orofin

Frontend Developer

Phone Number: +2349064877285 Email: orofinadedamola@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/adedamola-orofin/ Website: https://adedamolaorofin.web.app/

Profile Summary

I am a self-motivated and enthusiastic frontend developer with a passion for software engineering and am eager to contribute to team success in a thriving, exciting, and growing company through hard work, attention to detail, and excellent organizational skills. With less than two years of experience, I understand web development and the tools required. I am motivated to grow, excel, learn and unlearn while giving my utmost best to my employer.

Education

Federal University of Technology Akure

Ondo, Nigeria 2018-2024

B.Eng in Information and Communication Technology.

Coursework in Software Development Techniques, Agile, Software Development Life cycle,

Software Development Techniques, Case tools, Computer Science.

Current CGPA: 4.66

Work Experience

Empower Her Community

Lagos, Nigeria June 2022 - Present

Frontend Developer (Volunteer)

Collaborating with other developers to ensure the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs.

- Developing, debugging, and testing reusable code.
- Using Slack for communication, Git for version control, and Github to collaborate.
- Collaborated with another developer to build a task productivity app with React and Firebase(https://ehc-todoapp.web.app /).

Weixel Tech Ondo, Nigeria Frontend Developer Intern April 2021 - Nov 2021

Collaborated with other frontend engineers during development processes to confirm creative proposals, design, and code for the right solutions for a defined problem.

- Coded using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Exercised my communication skills by keeping in touch with my supervisor throughout the project's lifecycle via email and
- Researched emerging web technologies for possible incorporation into products

Bright Network London, UK Technology Intern Dec 2020 - Jan 2021

Learned SDLC best practices within an Agile software environment to produce rapid iterations for clients.

- Learned the importance of effective communication and time management in teamwork.
- Delivered the final task in time by exercising my time-management skill.
- Worked on a presentation that involved pitching a new software and summarizing the project's life cycle.

Skills

Programming Skills: HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, TypeScript.

FrameWorks/Libraries/Systems: React, Firebase, Material-UI, Git, Github.

Soft Skills: Communication, Teamwork and Collaboration, Organization, Time management, Problem-solving.

Certifications

May 2022 - Soft-Skills Training, Jobberman.

• Jan 2021 - Technology Internship Experience, Bright Network.

Reference

Kolade Adetoyinbo

Fullstack Developer, Weixel Tech

Phone: +2347036654293

Email: kolade.adetoyinbo@weixeltech.com